## **ARCHITA RAY**

+1 (765)-543-6931 | archita.fall23@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/archita-ray-06dec97/| github.com/archita612| archita.vercel.app

#### PROFILE

Seasoned Data Analyst with 4 years of experience in Retail, E-comm & CPG industries seeking full-time analytics role from Aug'24

**Programming Languages:** SQL, Python (NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Beautiful Soup, NLTK, Scikit-Learn, Keras), R **Certifications:** Tableau Desktop, Google Advanced Data Analytics Professional, Azure (AZ-900), AWS (CLF-C02) **Software & Platforms:** MySQL, Jupyter, VS Code, RStudio, SAS EM, Git, Excel (@Risk, Minitab, Solver), PowerPoint, GCP, OBI, ODI, MS Projects, SmartSheets, Power BI (DAX, Power Query), Tableau

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Purdue University, Daniels School of Business**

West Lafayette, United States

Master of Science in Business Analytics and Information Management (STEM)

Aug 2024

**SRM Institute of Science and Technology** 

Chennai, India

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics & Communication Engineering

May 2019

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Kearney (Purdue Student Labs) Analytics Consultant**

Chicago, United States Jan 2024 – Apr 2024

• Improved retention by ~4% at CPG warehouses by leading a multifaceted data analysis project blending qualitative (online surveys) and quantitative (regression & conjoint) analysis to identify core drivers of employee attrition.

# Flipkart (Formerly Myntra)

Bangalore, India Mar 2021 – Mar 2023

Data Analyst

- Attained 100% data accuracy in tracking and preventing potential losses of up to 80,000 USD monthly by automating the generation of pendency and loss reports using R and SQL for live hourly insights on various KPIs.
- Boosted conversion rate (item reintegration to inventory) by 41.2% by evaluating the return quality of different suppliers using 40+ live reports developed and maintained in Excel and Data Studio dashboards.
- Enhanced warehouse operations visibility by up to 97% by collaborating with leadership to identify bottlenecks and increased re-inventorization from 91.7% to 96.4% using custom metrics and Tableau for data visualization.
- Trimmed total cost of operation by \$6,000/month by analyzing employee workflows and lead times of warehouses using Google Forms and Data Studio to improve quarterly productivity goals.

#### **IBM**

Bangalore, India Jan 2020 – Dec 2020

### Associate Systems Engineer

- Accomplished seamless data transfer with 97% accuracy from Siebel DB to Oracle data warehouse by performing ETL jobs and debugging loads on Oracle Data Integration while maintaining data quality and transformation integrity.
- Reduced reporting time by 40% via data modeling techniques for real-time updates by optimizing OBIEE client reports.
- Oversaw a team of 3 data engineers to drive consistent data infrastructure updates at different stages of the project lifecycle (Develop/UAT/Prod) by managing bi-weekly meetings with a key Energy client.

#### Mu Sigma

#### **Trainee Decision Scientist**

Bangalore, India Sep 2019 – Dec 2019

- Executed univariate time series analysis & demand forecasting on 2-year-old sales data to inform strategic sales planning.
- Assessed customer reactions to a client company's new product launch by conducting sentiment analysis on 10k+ tweets.

#### PROJECT EXPERIENCE

- **Airbnb Success Factors in Houston:** Unveiled pivotal factors for Airbnb superhost status and earning potential in Houston, leveraging statistical models: polynomial regression (86% Valid R2) for occupancy rating prediction, and Random Forest (84.89% Valid R2) for overall property rating.
- **TikTok's claims classification**: Developed a predictive model differentiating claims from opinions of videos, using Random Forest, Gradient Boosting, and XGBoost, achieving an exceptional 98.04% recall with the best model.
- **Email Campaign Optimization:** Revamped marketing database at ASP OL Media by applying data modeling, SQL optimization, and normalization expertise, driving a 20% uplift in campaign performance, and enhancing data integrity.

#### LEADERSHIP ACTIVITIES, AFFILIATIONS, HONORS

- At Flipkart, led monthly SQL and Tableau workshops, empowering warehouse staff & business stakeholders for real-time production monitoring resulting in a 17% boost in warehouse productivity.
- Future Edelman Impact Award: Purdue Finalist (2024) for capstone project's business impact (awaiting results).
- Mentored team members and served as analytics SME for the 8-member cross-functional team at Flipkart.
- Crafted strategic solution for Lafayette's 13,735-unit housing gap, securing second runner-up in a business case competition.

Open to Relocate